Guide to the James Kirkup Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
James Kirkup papers
1890-2007
1940-2007
GEN MSS 773
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
79.31
(200 boxes) + 2 rolls and 4 broadside folders
The James Kirkup Papers includes correspondence, writings, photographs, audiovisual material, personal documents and memorabilia that document the life and work of British author James Kirkup.The papers span his writing career, from early school papers to printouts of digital books published in the 2000s, and include documentation of the diverse genres of Kirkup's research and writing. The papers document not only Kirkup's life and work, but also pacifism as a theme in literature, twentieth-century gay life, émigré life in Japan, 20th century literature and poetry (especially haiku), and Kirkup's family history. Prominent correspondents include Akiko Takemoto and Muriel Metcalfe.
Kirkup, James, 1918-2009
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from James Kirkup and from Hawthorn Books on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 1994-2009.
Printouts of virtual books: gift of Brindin Press, 2003.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 177-178 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Associated Materials
Other material by or relating to James Kirkup, including letters to Akiko Takemoto, can be found by searching Orbis (Yale's Online Catalog).
Related material can be found in the James Kirkup Collection in South Shields, cataloged at http://www.thejameskirkupcollection.co.uk/collection.html.
Arrangement
Organized into seven series: I. Correspondence, 1937-2007. II. Writings, 1938-2007. III. Personal Papers and Memorabilia, circa 1920-1997. IV. Audiovisual Material, 1993-2002. V. Visual Material, circa 1890-2000s. VI. Printed Material, 1930s-2000s. VII. Manuscript Material Removed from Books, 1960s-2000s.
James Kirkup, 1918-2009
James Kirkup, prolific author and translator, produced hundreds of works of poetry, autobiography, drama, travel memoir, translation and obituary. Kirkup occasionally used pen names, including James Falconer, Jun Honda, Andrew James, Taeko Kawai, Felix Liston, Edward Raeburn, and Ivy B. Summerforest.Kirkup was born April 23, 1918 in South Shields, England, lived much of his life in Japan, and died May 10, 2009 in Andorra.
Scope and Contents
The James Kirkup Papers includes correspondence, writings, photographs, audiovisual material, personal documents and memorabilia that document the life and work of British author James Kirkup. The papers span his writing career, from early school papers to digital books published in the 2000s, and include documentation of the diverse genres of Kirkup's research and writing: autobiography, poetry, travel writing, obituaries, novels, dramatic works, and translations. The papers document not only Kirkup's life and work, but also pacifism as a theme in literature, twentieth-century gay life, émigré life in Japan, twentieth-century literature and poetry (especially haiku), and Kirkup's family history. Prominent correspondents include Akiko Takemoto and Muriel Metcalfe.
Authors, English -- 20th Century -- Archives; Autobiography; English drama -- 20th Century; Emigration and immigration -- Japan; English poetry; Gay authors; Gay men; Haiku; Haiku -- Translations into English; Homosexuality and literature; Obituaries; Pacifism -- Great Britain; Poetry; Translating and interpreting; Travelers' writings, British; Notebooks; Photographs; Audiovisual materials; Sound recordings; Video recordings; LGBTQ resource; Kirkup, James, 1918-2009; Metcalfe, Muriel; Takemoto, Akiko, 1937-
- Correspondence, 1937-2007; Series I; 14.8; (36 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by correspondent. Unsorted general correspondence from the 1990s and 2000s, arranged roughly by year, is filed at the end of the series.
  Scope and Contents
  Correspondence (Series I), with dates ranging from the 1930s to the 2000s, is incoming unless otherwise indicated in the folder notes. Material in this series is chiefly professional in nature but also includes substantial files of correspondence with close friends such as Akiko Takemoto and Muriel Metcalfe. These files delve into both literary and personal topics, including the translation of poetry. Muriel Metcalfe's correspondence (filed under Sonia Lawson) includes drawings by her and by Fred Lawson. Other correspondents include publishers, translators, and fellow authors, including authors whose works Kirkup translated.
  Some correspondence related to a particular work is filed in Writings (Series II).
  - "A" General, 1951-1980s (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Ainley, Richard, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Atlas Press, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "B" General, 1937-1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bancroft, Ian, 1943-1969 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Blundell, Colin
    Related Archival Materials note
    See: Hub Editions
  - Blyth, R.H., 1964 February 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Brindin Press, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - British Broadcasting Corporation, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - British Haiku Society (correspondence, notes and ephemera), 1990s (Box 2, Folder 9-13)
  - Burleigh, David, 1989-1992 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - "C" General, 1942-1970 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Carcanet New Press, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Causley, Charles, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Ceccatty, René de, 1985-1994 (Box 3, Folder 18-19)
  - Cekolj, Marijan, 1988-1992 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Cherkeshi, Sadi O., 1940s (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Childe, Wilfred Roland, 1950-1952 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Clements, Marshall, 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 23-24)
  - Cloud (Publisher), 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Cobb, David, 1990-1994 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Constable, Charles, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Crane, David, 1990s (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - "D" General, 1944-1994 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Davis, Gloria Evans, 1985-1990 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    Includes poems.
  - Drevet, Patrick, 1989-1994 (Box 4, Folder 31-32)
    Includes clippings and printed versions of A Room in the Woods, by Drevet, English translation by Kirkup.
  - Durham University, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Eason, Tom (incoming and outgoing, copies of letters from 1940-1941), undated (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Elliott, William, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Encounter magazine, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - "F" General, 1965-1969, undated (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Fausset, Hugh, 1943-1944 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Fergar, Feyyaz, 1940-1944, undated (Box 5, Folder 39-42)
  - Fischer, Rüdiger, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Fleet, Dorothy, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Fukuda, Tsutomu, 1970s-1980s (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - "G" General, 1951-1987, undated (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - George Weidenfeld & Nicolson Limited, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Gibson, James, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Gifford, Barry, 1990s (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Girdlestone, Professor (draft and copies), 1939, 1987, undated (Box 6, Folder 50-53)
  - Godden, Rumer, 1967-1990 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - "H" General, 1953-1970 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Higham, Charles, undated (Box 6, Folder 56)
    Includes poems by Higham.
  - Hogg, James, 1990s (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Hub Editions, 1992-1993 (Box 6, Folder 58-59)
  - Hubbell, Lindley Williams, 1979-1996 (Box 7, Folder 60-62)
    Includes correspondence with others about Lindley Williams Hubbell.
  - "I" General, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Ito, Masako, 1960s, undated (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - "J" General, 1953, undated (Box 7, Folder 65)
  - Japan PEN Club, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 66)
    Includes correspondence and clippings about the Japan PEN Club Prize.
  - "K" General, 1947-1951 (Box 7, Folder 67)
  - Kaplin, Ivor, 1980s-1990s (Box 7, Folder 68)
  - Kavanagh, Rik (Box 7, Folder 69)
  - Kervern, Alain, 1990s (Box 7, Folder 70)
  - King, Francis, 1986-1994 (Box 8, Folder 71-72)
  - Kirkup, Jean J., 1957 June 25 (Box 8, Folder 73)
  - Kirkup, Mary, 1968-1969 (Box 8, Folder 74)
  - Kobayashi, Atsuo, 1971-1988, undated (Box 8, Folder 75)
  - Kranz, Gisbert, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 76)
  - Kubota, Mr. (incoming, including copies), undated (Box 8, Folder 77)
  - Kyoto University (letter of resignation), 1988 May 22 (Box 8, Folder 78)
  - "L" General, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 79)
  - Lawrence, Bill, 1943-1945 (Box 8, Folder 80)
  - Lawson, Sonia, circa 1940-1998 (Box 8, Folder 81-85)
    Includes correspondence with and about Muriel Metcalf.
  - Lawson, Sonia (continued), circa 1940-1998 (Box 9, Folder 86-94)
  - "M" General, 1945-1999 (Box 10, Folder 95)
  - Machin, Roger, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 96)
  - Martin, [Rena?], 1964 (Box 10, Folder 97)
  - Metcalf, Muriel
    See: Lawson, Sonia
  - Miura, Fumiko (outgoing), 1964-1994 (Box 10, Folder 98)
  - Morris, Ivan, 1969-1971 (Box 10, Folder 99)
  - "N" General, 1962-1971 (Box 10, Folder 100)
  - Nagayama, Mokuo, 1970s (Box 10, Folder 101)
  - Nakano, Michio, 1966-1994 (Box 10, Folder 102)
    See also: Carcanet New Press
  - New Directions, 1960s (Box 10, Folder 103)
  - The New Yorker, 1964-1969 (Box 10, Folder 104)
  - Nichols, Ross, 1945-1950, undated (Box 10, Folder 105-106)
  - Niel, Jean-Baptiste (incoming and outgoing, accompanied by material related to Kirkup's translations and reviews), 1992 (Box 11, Folder 107-108)
  - "O" General, 1968, undated (Box 11, Folder 109)
  - Obata, Takeshi, 1995 August (Box 11, Folder 110)
  - Old School Press, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 111)
  - Orton, Iris (incoming and outgoing), 1950-1987 (Box 11, Folder 112-115)
    Includes poetry by Iris Orton.
  - Orton, Iris (incoming and outgoing) (continued), 1950-1987 (Box 12, Folder 116-117)
  - Owen, Peter
    See: Peter Owen Ltd.
  - "P" General, 1954-1993 (Box 12, Folder 118)
  - Parker, Peter, 1986-1989 (Box 12, Folder 119)
  - Pastre, Geneviève, 1990-1992 (Box 12, Folder 120)
  - Paul, Angela, 1943-1992 (Box 12, Folder 121-122)
  - Paul, David, 1940s-1960s (Box 12, Folder 123-125)
  - Peter Owen Ltd. (correspondence, incoming and outgoing, and contracts), 1990-1997 (Box 12, Folder 126-127)
  - Petter, Angela H.
    See: Paul, Angela
  - Purdy, James, 1995-1996 (Box 13, Folder 128)
  - "R" General, 1951-1981, undated (Box 13, Folder 129)
  - Roberts, Walter, 1940s (Box 13, Folder 130)
  - Rockingham Press, 1993-1994 (Box 13, Folder 131-132)
    Includes proofs of Throwback
  - Ronson, Herbert, 1986-1989 (Box 13, Folder 133)
  - Russell, Peter, 1998 (Box 13, Folder 134)
  - "S" General, 1953-1994 (Box 13, Folder 135)
  - Sato, Kenji, undated (Box 13, Folder 136)
  - Seibido Publishing Co. (incoming and outgoing), 1982-1991 (Box 13, Folder 137-138)
    Includes financial papers
  - Sekino, Seiji, 1960s-1980s (Box 13, Folder 139)
  - Shukuya, Mutsuo, 1995-1997 (Box 14, Folder 140-146)
  - Singh, Jasbir, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 147)
  - Skjöld, Birgit (including material related to a tribute to Birgit Skjöld), 1978-1984 (Box 14, Folder 148-149)
  - South Shields Gazette (outgoing), 1940 (Box 15, Folder 150)
  - Spender, Stephen, 1977-1993 (Box 15, Folder 151-152)
  - Spiese, Robert, 1999 (Box 15, Folder 153)
  - Stevenson, George, 1971-1973 (Box 15, Folder 154-155)
    Includes drafts of poetry and other writings by James Kirkup
  - "T" General, 1940-1981, undated (Box 15, Folder 156)
  - Takemoto, Akiko (incoming and outgoing), circa 1967-1991 (Box 15, Folder 157-161)
  - Takemoto, Akiko (incoming and outgoing) (continued), circa 1967-1991 (Box 16, Folder 162-168)
  - Takemoto, Akiko (incoming and outgoing) (continued), circa 1967-1991 (Box 17, Folder 169-176)
  - Tamaguchi, Takeyoshi (incoming and outgoing), 1969-1982 (Box 18, Folder 177-181)
  - Tebb, Barry (poems and letters, typescript and printed version), undated (Box 18, Folder 182-183)
  - Temenos Academy, 2004 (Box 18, Folder 184)
  - Thorp, Michael, 1993-1994 (Box 18, Folder 185)
    See also: Cloud (Publisher)
  - Tokunaga, Shozo (incoming and outgoing), 1959-1994 (Box 19, Folder 186-189)
  - "W"-"Y" General, 1967-1993, undated (Box 19, Folder 190)
  - Yamano, Shigehiko, 1990s (Box 19, Folder 191)
  - Letters from Readers (including Bernaud Bergouzi and Robin Athill), 1940s-1960s (Box 20, Folder 192)
  - Letters from Libraries, 1960s-1990s (Box 20, Folder 193)
  - Letters from children in South Shields about "Sorrows, Passions and Alarms", 1980 (Box 20, Folder 194)
  - Letters from Japanese students, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 195)
  - James Kirkup Newsletter, 1979-1980s (Box 20, Folder 196-201)
  - James Kirkup Newsletter (continued), 1979-1980s (Box 21, Folder 202-203)
  - Unsorted personal and family letters (Box 21, Folder 204)
  - Unsorted general correspondence, 1990s (Box 21, Folder 205-207)
  - Unsorted general correspondence, 1990s (Box 22, Folder 208-213)
  - Unsorted general correspondence, 1990s (Box 23, Folder 214-218)
  - Unsorted general correspondence, 1990s (Box 24, Folder 219-224)
  - Unsorted general correspondence, 1990s (Box 25, Folder 225-229)
  - Unsorted general correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box 26, Folder 230-235)
  - Unsorted general correspondence, 1998-2000 (Box 27, Folder 236-241)
  - Unsorted general correspondence, 1999-2000 (Box 28, Folder 242-249)
  - Unsorted general correspondence, 2001 (Box 29, Folder 250-255)
  - Unsorted general correspondence, 2001-2003 (Box 30, Folder 256-261)
  - Unsorted general correspondence, 2002-2003 (Box 31, Folder 262-267)
  - Unsorted general correspondence, 2003-2004 (Box 32, Folder 268-273)
  - Unsorted general correspondence, 2004-2006 (Box 33, Folder 274-278)
  - Unsorted general correspondence, 2006-2007 (Box 34, Folder 279-281)
  - Unsorted general correspondence, undated (Box 34, Folder 282-285)
  - Unsorted general correspondence, undated (Box 35, Folder 286-294)
  - Unsorted general correspondence, undated (Box 36, Folder 295-305)
- Writings, 1938-2007; Series II; 54.42; (135 boxes)
  Organized into nine subseries: Poetry; Works of Prose; Translations by James Kirkup; Drama, Opera, and Music; Obituaries by James Kirkup; Notebooks; Reviews; Unidentified and Unsorted Writings; and Writings of Others. Unsorted writings are also filed at the end of each subseries listing.
  Writings (Series II) include drafts and/or proofs of many of Kirkup's writings and translations, spanning diverse genres: autobiography, poetry, travel writing, obituaries, novels, and dramatic works. Also included are notebooks containing drafts of poems and travel diaries. In addition to drafts and proofs, some files include correspondence, photographs or ephemera related to the research and publication of the work.
  Some works are authored under one of Kirkup's many pen names, including James Falconer, Jun Honda, Andrew James, Taeko Kawai, Felix Liston, Edward Raeburn, and Ivy B. Summerforest.
  Of particular interest are the "Blasphemy Files" containing material related to Kirkup's interest in this topic, which stems from the 1976 publication of Kirkup's poem "The Love that Dares to Speak Its Name" in Gay News and the resulting trial and conviction of editor Denis Lemon. These files include correspondence, clippings and research material related to blasphemy, particularly in England.
  - Poetry
    Poetry is organized under two headings: Titled Works and Untitled Works.
    - Titled Works
      Arranged alphabetically by title.
      - Abstracts, poems including "Predictability," typescript, undated (Box 37, Folder 306)
      - "Adachigahara," holograph and typescript, first draft, 1996 (Box 37, Folder 307)
      - "Adolescences" / Sound of the Fountain, typescript, undated (Box 37, Folder 308)
      - "Aeterae Memoria Patris," typescript, undated (Box 37, Folder 309)
      - All Sorts, typescript, undated (Box 37, Folder 310-311)
      - "Annunciation," typescript and holograph, 1969 (Box 37, Folder 312)
      - An Anthology of English Lyrics Charming and Unconventional, recited by James Kirkup, printed, typed and handwritten poems, 1950s (Box 37, Folder 313-314)
      - Anthology of Modern Japanese Poetry, typescript, undated (Box 37, Folder 315-316)
      - The Authentic Touch, typescript (copies), undated (Box 38, Folder 317-318)
      - The Best Way to Travel, Passages from the works of Zhuangzi, typescript and printed version, 2004 (Box 38, Folder 319-320)
      - A Bewick Bestiary, typescript, 1971 (Box 38, Folder 321)
      - Blithe Spirit, Volume 4 Number 3, 1994 (Box 38, Folder 322)
      - Blue Bamboo
        - Drafts, holograph and typescript, undated (Box 38, Folder 323-325)
        - Colin Blundell: musical setting of "Fools," haiku, manuscript (copy), undated (Box 38, Folder 326)
      - The Body Servant, typescript and proofs, 1971 (Box 38, Folder 327-328)
      - A Book of Tanka, typescript and related material, undated (Box 39, Folder 329-330)
      - Burning Giraffes / "Zentsuji," typescript and proofs, 1996 (Box 39, Folder 331-332)
      - A Certain Chaos, selection, typescript, undated (Box 39, Folder 333)
      - "Christ Scarecrow"
        - Holograph, typescript, and postcard, 1988 (Box 39, Folder 334)
        - Typescript and related material, 1988 (Box 39, Folder 335)
      - Christmas Poems, Australian Broadcasting Commission, typescript and related material, 1980 (Box 39, Folder 336)
      - City of AIDS, typescript and copies, undated (Box 39, Folder 337)
      - Collected Longer Poems. Volume 2: Hermitage Verses, revised, typescript and copy of printed version, 1996 (Box 39, Folder 338)
      - A Correct Compassion
        - Notebook, Leeds, holograph, 1951 (Box 39, Folder 339)
        - Partial typescript, 1952 (Box 39, Folder 340)
        - Typescript and related material, including Leeds essay, undated (Box 39, Folder 341)
        - Radio script, typescript and correspondence, 1974 (Box 39, Folder 342)
        - Photograph of heart operation, 1979 May 25 (Box 39, Folder 343)
        - Correspondence and related material, 1953-1974 (Box 39, Folder 344)
        - Typescript and related materials, undated (Box 39, Folder 345)
      - The Cosmic Shape, page proof, undated (Box 40, Folder 346)
      - Counting to 9999, Haiku and Tanka, holograph and typescript, 1995, undated (Box 40, Folder 347-348)
      - The Creation, holograph and typescript, undated (Box 40, Folder 349)
      - The Delivered Lovers, A sequence of poems, holograph and typescript, 1942-1943 (Box 40, Folder 350-351)
      - Dengonban Messages, typescript and copy, undated (Box 40, Folder 352-353)
      - The Descent Into the Cave and Other Poems, typescripts, undated (Box 40, Folder 354-356)
        See also: The Drowned Sailor.
      - A Desert Island of the Mind, typescript (copy), undated (Box 40, Folder 357)
      - The Drowned Sailor, drafts, typescript and printed version, 1947, undated (Box 40, Folder 358-360)
        Includes typescripts of The Submerged Village and The Descent Into the Cave
      - Dry Morning After a Wet Night, typescript and holograph, undated (Box 41, Folder 361)
      - First Fireworks, drafts, holograph and typescript, 1993 (Box 41, Folder 362)
      - Formulas for Chaos, typescript and mock-up, 1994 (Box 41, Folder 363)
      - The Glass Fable, typescripts, undated (Box 41, Folder 364-367)
      - The Guitar Player of Zuiganji, typescripts, 1985, undated (Box 42, Folder 368-373)
      - He Dreamt He was a Butterfly, typescript (copy) and printed version, 1997 (Box 42, Folder 374-376)
      - In a Manner of Speaking, typescript (copy), undated (Box 42, Folder 377)
      - "In Memory of Takeyoshi Yamaguchi," holograph, typescript and photograph of Yamaguchi, 1972, 1985 (Box 42, Folder 378)
      - Independent, Poems and Haiku, undated (Box 42, Folder 379)
      - Indications, review by Hugh Ianson Fausset, typescript carbon, 1943 (Box 43, Folder 380)
      - "An Island in the Sky," typescripts and copy, 2000s (Box 43, Folder 381-385)
      - Japan Marine, "Poems from photographs", typescript, carbon and photographs, 1964-1965 (Box 43, Folder 386-387)
      - Japanoramas, drafts, typescript and copies, accompanied by letters from Robert Kowalczyk, 1983, 1994 (Box 43, Folder 388-391)
      - Journey To A Microsecond, A Poem For Radio, typescript carbon, undated (Box 44, Folder 392)
      - Juganji Temple, holograph draft and associated material, 1966 (Box 44, Folder 393)
      - The Last Man, typescript, undated (Box 44, Folder 394)
      - A Lingering Spell: Tanka Improvisations, typescripts, 1996, undated (Box 44, Folder 395-397)
      - The Little Treatise of Anatomy, typescript, 1970, undated (Box 44, Folder 398-399)
      - Look At It This Way, typescript (copy), undated (Box 44, Folder 400)
      - Mainichi Daily News, haiku clippings, 1980s (Box 44, Folder 401-402)
      - Many Lined Poems, chapbook, undated (Box 44, Folder 403)
      - "My Mother's Knitting," typescript, undated (Box 44, Folder 404)
      - "New Criterion Poetry Prize," poems, typescript, 2000 (Box 44, Folder 405)
      - "New Nations and Peoples," holograph, undated (Box 44, Folder 406)
      - The Night Visit, typescript (copy), undated (Box 44, Folder 407)
      - Noems, One-line haiku and senryu, typescript and related correspondence, 1978 (Box 45, Folder 408)
      - Noems, Koans and a Navel Display, "senryu and one liners," drafts, holograph, 1992-1995 (Box 45, Folder 409)
      - An Off Centre: Autobiographical Poems, typescript, 1987-1989 (Box 45, Folder 410)
      - "On my 66th birthday," holograph and typescript, 1984 (Box 45, Folder 411)
      - Oneliners online, typescript and copy, undated (Box 45, Folder 412-416)
      - One-Man Band: Poems without Words, typescript and copy, undated (Box 45, Folder 417-418)
      - Paper Windows, poems from Japan, typescript, typescript carbon, and page proofs, 1967-1968, undated (Box 46, Folder 419-424)
      - Pikadon, typescript and related material, 1990s (Box 46, Folder 425-428)
      - Platitude Volume II. No. 11, 1941? (Box 46, Folder 429)
      - The Pleasures of Poetry, "Various poem drafts", typescript, undated (Box 46, Folder 430)
      - A Poem A Page, an unpublished anthology, 1980s (Box 47, Folder 431)
      - "Private Parts"
        See: Transmental Vibrations
      - The Prodigal Son, drafts and proof, 1959, undated (Box 47, Folder 432-433)
      - Refusal To Conform, typescript, 1963 (Box 47, Folder 434-436)
      - Rehearsals for Departure, drafts, typescript and copies, undated (Box 47, Folder 437-439)
      - "Scenes from Sutcliffe," typescript and printd version, circa 1981 (Box 48, Folder 440-443)
      - The Sense of the Visit, drafts, holograph and typescript, and proofs, 1983-1984 (Box 48, Folder 444-453)
      - "September Poem," holograph and typescript, 1998 (Box 49, Folder 454)
      - Shepherding Winds, printed version, 1969 (Box 49, Folder 455)
      - Shields Sketches, typescript, printed version and related material, 1999-2000 (Box 49, Folder 456-457)
      - "Shoji," typescript and holograph, undated (Box 49, Folder 458)
      - Shooting Stars, drafts, typescript, and printed version, 1993 (Box 49, Folder 459-465)
      - Short Takes, typescript (copies), undated (Box 50, Folder 466-467)
      - The Sleeper in the Earth, typescript carbon, undated (Box 50, Folder 468)
      - "Snowviewing," holograph and typescript, undated (Box 50, Folder 469)
      - "Something for Everybody," typescript (copy), undated (Box 50, Folder 470)
      - "Space Station Ryoanji," typescript, undated (Box 50, Folder 471)
      - A Spring Journey, typescript and page proofs, 1954 (Box 50, Folder 472-473)
      - Strange Attractors, typescript and related material, 1995 (Box 50, Folder 474)
      - The Submerged Village
        - Typescript and carbon, 1951 (Box 50, Folder 475-476)
        - Piano solo by Richard Benger (copy), undated (Box 50, Folder 477)
      - TankAlphabet, printed by Old School Press, 2001, 2004 (Box 50, Folder 478)
      - Tatouages Automatiques Equivoques, Poems by J. Kirkup in French, holograph and typescript, undated (Box 50, Folder 479)